essentialtravelinfo.com 2011-06-03

# Privacy Policy - Essential Travel Info

## Introduction

Essential Travel Info is a division of R&V Business Services (Pty) Ltd a private company that also owns and operates AA Travel Guides in South Africa.

We are committed to protecting your privacy. We aim to maintain consistently high levels of best practice in our processing of personal and/or sensitive personal data.

## How we use information you provide us

We use the information we receive from you to provide goods and/or services that you request, to communicate with you, and to personalise our information sent to you. We do not sell, trade, or rent your personal information to others.

We store all the information you provide us, including information provided via forms you complete on our website, and information which we may collect from your browsing. Our server, in common with nearly all web servers, logs each page that is downloaded from the site.

We store information you provide to us for the purpose of making accommodation enquiries or bookings, to be able to send you books that you order, or to use our mapping service. Such information is passed on electronically to establishments at which you enquire in order that they may respond to you.

We ask for your home, cellular telephone number, and email address to enable us to contact you in relation to an enquiry you have made, to contact you about relevant products or services, to contact you if there is a problem with your order, or there is another genuine reason for doing so. If you provide us with credit or debit card details in order to pay for a service or product, we will keep such details secure and ensure that the details are only used further with your consent and/or for the purposes of any appropriate refunds.

When you enter a contest or other promotional feature, we may ask for your name, address, telephone numbers and email address so we can administer the contest and notify winners.

Occasionally, we may also use the information we collect to notify you by post, telephone, mobile telephone, email and SMS about new or existing Essential Travel Info or AA Travel Guides services, products and special offers we think you'll find valuable.

Generally by providing the requested data you consent to Essential Travel Info and AA Travel Guides South Africa using that data for administrative purposes and for informing you of other products and services by letter, SMS, telephone and/or email. We may also use the information we collect to occasionally notify you about important functionality changes to the website.

Each time you receive marketing information or a message, you have the option to decline to receive further marketing information from us. This is known as an 'opt-out'. If you wish to exercise the opt-out please email us on [opt-out@essentialtravelinfo.com](mailto:opt-out@essentialtravelinfo.com) advising all email addresses for which you wish to opt out.

## Disclosure of information to third parties

We do not sell, trade or rent your information and will never disclose information about you to third parties, except to fulfill your specific orders for a product or information in the event that third parties deliver the relevant service.  
If we provide information to a third party (either a provider of a product or service, or an external data processing agency such as a mailing house) we will exercise the strictest control over the third party contractually, requiring it and any of its agents and/or suppliers to:

  * maintain the security and confidentiality of the information and restrict access to those of its own employees; 
  * use the data for the agreed purpose only and prevent it being used for any other purpose by any other party; 
  * refrain from communicating with you other than concerning the product in question; 
  * return the data to us at the conclusion of any contract term and destroy or delete any copies made of all or any part of the information unless copies are needed to be kept to comply with regulations. 

In addition, we will restrict the information disclosed to the absolute minimum necessary, for example, to provide the product or service. 

## Changes to our Privacy Policy

If we decide to change our Privacy Policy, we will update all relevant documentation and post any changes onto our websites so that you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances we disclose it.
